Samuel Tracy

Phone: (916) 764-9002 Email: stracy@g.harvard.edu Web: https://seasamgo.github.io

Ph.D. student in Biostatistics at Harvard University focusing on methods for failure time data and single-cell sequencing data. My advisor is Dr. Guo-Cheng Yuan. Interests include sampling techniques, optimization theory, missingness, clustering methods, and dimensionality reduction. I am also an advocate for open-source development, reproducible research and diversity in STEM.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. Biostatistics	Harvard University	20191
M.A. Biostatistics	Harvard University	2016
B.S. Applied Mathematics, magna cum laude	UC San Diego	2014

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Research Consultant	09/2017 – present
---------------------	-------------------

Harvard University, Boston, MA

Department of Biostatistics Consulting Center

Student Intern 04/2013 – 06/2013

CTRI, San Diego, CA

Clinical data visualization and analysis

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant 01/2016 – present

T.H. Chan Harvard School of Public Health, Boston, MA

BST 210 Applied Regression Analysis (Spring 2016 and 2017)

BST 226 Applied Longitudinal Analysis (Spring 2018)

Instructor and Administrator

01/2015 - 08/2017

StatStart, Boston, MA

Student-run high school program in statistical computing for minorities in STEM (Summer 2015, 2016 and 2017)

Teaching Assistant

09/2013 - 06/2014

UC San Diego, San Diego, CA

MATH 10ABC Calculus Series (Fall 2013, Winter 2014 and Spring 2014)

Academic Liaison 01/2013 – 03/2013

Fallbrook High School, Fallbrook, CA

All-subjects tutor and liaison through the UC San Diego Educational Studies Department

1

¹anticipated

PROJECTS

Chen, T., Tracy, S., Uno, H. Minimal-area confidence bands for failure time data.

Tracy, S., Dries, R., Yuan, G.C. scRNA-seq dropout imputation via subsampling of genes.

Tracy, S., Yuan, G.C. Scoring lineage prediction with single-cell data.

PUBLICATIONS

Talbot, O., Ocampo, A., Tracy, S., Mosesso, K., Rahman, A., and Pagano, M. StatStart 2015. *ASA: The Statistics Teacher Network*, 87: 4-8, 2016.

SKILLS

Programming – R, MATLAB, Stata, Java, C++, Python

SOFTWARE

Co-creator and maintainer of the R package optband (on CRAN and GitHub), a package for statistical confidence bands applied to failure time data and optimized by area.

REFERENCES

Yuan, Guo-Cheng

Associate Professor, Department of Biostatistics, Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health Address: 360 Longwood Ave, Room 1060, Boston, MA 02215

Tel: 617-582-8532 Email: gcyuan@jimmy.harvard.edu

Xu, Ronghui

Professor, Department of Mathematics, University of California, San Diego

Address: 9500 Gilman Drive #0112, La Jolla, CA 92093

Tel: 858-534-6380 Email: rxu@ucsd.edu

¹anticipated